<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Metaschema Information Modeling Framework on Metaschema</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/</link><description>Recent content in Metaschema Information Modeling Framework on Metaschema</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Metaschema Module</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/specification/syntax/module/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/specification/syntax/module/</guid><description>Metaschema Module A Metaschema module is represented using the top-level XML element &amp;lt;METASCHEMA&amp;gt;.
For example:
&amp;lt;?xml version=&amp;#34;1.0&amp;#34; encoding=&amp;#34;UTF-8&amp;#34;?&amp;gt; &amp;lt;METASCHEMA xmlns=&amp;#34;http://csrc.nist.gov/ns/oscal/metaschema/1.0&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;schema-name&amp;gt;Computer Model&amp;lt;/schema-name&amp;gt; &amp;lt;schema-version&amp;gt;0.0.5&amp;lt;/schema-version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;short-name&amp;gt;computer&amp;lt;/short-name&amp;gt; &amp;lt;namespace&amp;gt;http://example.com/ns/computer&amp;lt;/namespace&amp;gt; &amp;lt;json-base-uri&amp;gt;http://example.com/ns/computer&amp;lt;/json-base-uri&amp;gt; &amp;lt;remarks&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This is an example model to describe the components of a computer.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The &amp;#34;computer&amp;#34; element is the root element of this model.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/remarks&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!-- followed by a series of imports, then a series of definitions --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/METASCHEMA&amp;gt; Attributes:
Attribute Data Type Use Default Value Section @abstract yes or no optional no Header: Abstract Module Elements:</description></item><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/specification/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/specification/overview/</guid><description>Overview The Metaschema Information Modeling Framework provides a means to represent an information model for a given information domain, consisting of many related information elements, in a data format neutral form. By abstracting information modeling away from data format specific forms, the Metaschema Information Modeling Framework provides a means to consistently and sustainably maintain an information model, while avoiding the need to maintain each derivative data format individually. By consolidating information model maintenance into a single representation, significant time can be saved over other approaches that require each data format to be maintained individually.</description></item><item><title>Definitions</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/specification/syntax/definitions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/specification/syntax/definitions/</guid><description>Definitions A definition in a Metaschema module declares a reusable information element within an information model.
In graph theoretical terms, a definition provides a declaration of a graph node and any associated edges that form a given subgraph shape.
In object-oriented terms, a definition provides a declaration of a class, along with any associated class members.
The following subsections describe the common syntax for all definition types, followed by the semantic and syntax details of each type of definition.</description></item><item><title>Information Modeling</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/specification/information-modeling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/specification/information-modeling/</guid><description>Information Modeling The following diagram illustrates the relationships between information modeling concepts and the core structures provided by the Metaschema Framework.
An information model is an abstract representation of information from a given information domain. An information model is composed of a set of semantically well-defined information structures that each represent an information element in the information domain.
The primary purpose of the Metaschema Framework is to support the structured expression of an information model, which is represented as a Metaschema module.</description></item><item><title>Instances</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/specification/syntax/instances/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/specification/syntax/instances/</guid><description>Instances In a Metaschema module, complex information elements are created through composition. Through composition, an information element can be built by indicating which other information elements are used as its constituent parts.
An instance is used to declare an information element child within a parent information element. Each instance is a flag instance, field instance, or assembly instance, and either references an existing top-level definition by name or provides an inline definition.</description></item><item><title>Inline Definitions</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/specification/syntax/inline-definitions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/specification/syntax/inline-definitions/</guid><description>Inline Definitions Inline definitions are a mechanism to both define a named information element and instantiate it. In this way, inline definitions can be thought of as both definitions and instances, sharing most of the data elements of both.
Inline definitions are provided as a convenience to allow single-use information elements to be declared inline, within other definitions. Single-use, inline declarations are easier to maintain than a top-level definition that is referenced, since the maintainer doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to trace the reference.</description></item><item><title>Constraints</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/specification/syntax/constraints/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/specification/syntax/constraints/</guid><description>Constraints Note: This section of the specification is still a work in progress.
Metaschema modules can define different kinds of constraints to support data validation within and between document instances.
The types of constraints allowed for a given definition
&amp;lt;define-flag&amp;gt; constraints The following constraint types are allowed for &amp;lt;define-flag&amp;gt; definitions.
&amp;lt;allowed-values&amp;gt; &amp;lt;matches&amp;gt; &amp;lt;index-has-key&amp;gt; &amp;lt;expect&amp;gt; For each of these constraint types, use of the @target attribute is prohibited. This is because a flag constraint may only target the flag, since a flag has no child nodes.</description></item><item><title>Binding to XML, JSON, and YAML</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/specification/mapping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/specification/mapping/</guid><description>Binding to XML, JSON, and YAML Note: This section of the specification is still a work in progress.
XML, JSON, and YAML each use specialized terminology and format primitives. As a notation for an object-based data, YAML is fairly similar to JSON, while XML is quite different to the other two. While all data format describe tree structures (directed graphs), each format (with its implicit data model) has its particular design, which requires specification in detail.</description></item><item><title>Metaschema Data Types</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/specification/datatypes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/specification/datatypes/</guid><description>Data Types Used in Metaschema Metaschema is a strongly typed modeling language, that uses a collection of built in data types to represent data elements within a Metaschema-based model.
Metaschema&amp;rsquo;s data types represent a data-oriented, leaf nodes in a Metaschema-based model. These data types provide the basis for data elements that have clearly defined syntax and semantics.
There are 2 kinds of data types.
simple data types: that represent basic data value primitives with a specific syntax and semantics.</description></item><item><title>Metaschema Framework Specification Glossary</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/specification/glossary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/specification/glossary/</guid><description>Glossary The following terminology is used in this specification:
Assembly An assembly is defined as follows:
A complex named data element consisting of an optional set of flags and an optional sequence of model instances. An assembly does not have an associated value.
An assembly may reference or directly define zero or more flags. Flag instances associated with an assembly definition typically provide additional metadata used to identify or characterize the object represented by the assembly.</description></item><item><title>Contact Us</title><link>https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/contribute/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/contribute/contact/</guid><description>Contact Us Please email the project team with any questions you have about this project or if you are interested in getting involved.
Please visit our GitHub repository for more information, schemas, and examples.
A Gitter chat room is available for Metaschema discussions. This is a great place to discuss issues with the NIST developers and ask for assistance with building Metaschema-enabled tools. This room is also setup with GitHub integration, which provides a good summary of recent Metaschema GitHub repo activities within the chat room.</description></item></channel></rss>